<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeff Hilnbrand</title>
    <description>Hey there, I&#39;m Jeff. I like making cool things with cool people.
</description>
    <link>http://jhil.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://jhil.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 22:20:30 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 22:20:30 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Architecture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Fall 2014 semester, I enrolled in ARCH470: Architecture Technology. I had already taken a couple introductory architecture courses, but this would be my first advanced class on the topic. In ARCH470, I completed a series of assignments that actively used the curiculum’s software as I learned it. These tools included Rhinoceros, Grasshopper, V-Ray, Revit, Photoshop, 3ds Maxx, and SketchUp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The projects below are composed of presentation boards, highlighted assets, and maybe a process picture or two. The descriptions are pulled directly from the boards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-project&quot;&gt;Final Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sites like warehouses, factories, and farms are often repurposed for programs more appropriate for their locations. This project explores how a barn would be designed if it’s focus was coworking from the outset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barn was modeled parametrically in Grasshopper, using points from sine curves of various amplitudes to construct the distinct “double gambrel” roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barn provides public and private, indoor and outdoor, work and lounge spaces. The bottom floor contains the main coworking environment while the upper level includes a lounge and library. The outdoor walkway connects the two second-floor rooms and provides a scenic overlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-final-board.png&quot; alt=&quot;Final project board&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/O30qTHcVdeA?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/R33u5YYgfcg?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-final-comp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Final project composite&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-final-definition.png&quot; alt=&quot;Final project definition&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-final-diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;Final project diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Printing](/assets/architecture/architecture-final-printing.gif) --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment-3-visualization&quot;&gt;Assignment 3: Visualization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washington, D.C. promotes its ability to juggle culture and politics. In this assignment, I created a pavilion to match the city’s unique behaviours, serving as both a venue and a passive leisure site. The structure’s tesselating layers are suitible for a rally, concert, or lecture, providing optimal vantage points for 200 people. When not in scheduled use, tourists and locals can relax on the pavillion steps, unobtrusive to everyday happenings on the National Mall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pavilion’s wide podium targets its energy at the provided seating, but has the opportunity for expansion in the open area. Each step is accessible, though the far side has small elevated levels to accomodate photographers and other special situations. This design is parametric, able to expand outward with more levels or adjust the height interval and detail of the interior pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-3-board.png&quot; alt=&quot;3 board&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-3-diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;3 diagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;midterm-capturing-process&quot;&gt;Midterm: Capturing Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This assignment revolved around the Grasshopper plugin for Rhino. While it can be used to create a boundless number of structures, I was particularly interested in its data analysis tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Elk’s site mapping tools, I set out to fuse New York’s iconic streetmap and buildings with San Fracisco’s notoriously hilly topography. Elk employs OpenStreetMap.org and Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM) data from NASA, so this model simulates this concept with real data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project had several iterations. First, I pulled the NYC street data and planned to place it atop a randomly generated hill. Then I learned that Elk can support topography data, too. Later, I played with sliders to randomly generate building heights until my model looked similar to the NYC skyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-midterm-board.png&quot; alt=&quot;Midterm board&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-midterm-definition.png&quot; alt=&quot;Midterm board&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;assignment-2-digital-to-physical&quot;&gt;Assignment 2: Digital to Physical&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Assignment 2, we use paneling tools in Rhino to create unique experiences, considering the digital tools and physical prototyping that go into different structures. Inspired by observatories, helments visors, and the Death Star, this dome plays with light and dark to allow for different uses throughout the day. The outer skin has a pin that allows it to rotate around the inner skin, strategically revealing or hiding what is underneath. This structure is 3D printed to ensure rigidity and precision of the pin mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-2-board.png&quot; alt=&quot;2 board&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-2-render-open.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2 render open&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-2-render-half.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2 render half&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-2-render-closed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2 render closed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;folding&quot;&gt;Folding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/architecture/architecture-folding.png&quot; alt=&quot;Folding&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/architecture</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/architecture</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gorilla</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I teamed up with Eileen McMahon and Brandon Gotwalt in our Biologically Inspired Robotics course (ENME489L) to build a gorilla robot. The project involved studying a certain animal’s gait and build a robot that exhibits that animal’s walk cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/gorilla-silverback.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Silverback gorilla&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-robot&quot;&gt;Final Robot&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/final-side.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/final-front.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Front&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/final-top.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Top&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/final-knee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Knee&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/final-joint.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Joint&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/final-foot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Foot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research--building&quot;&gt;Research &amp;amp; Building&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Early sketches&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/whiteboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Whiteboard gait sketches&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/brandon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brandon&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/eileen.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eileen&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/top.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Early top&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/adjusting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Adjusting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;models&quot;&gt;Models&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/gait-1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Gait animation&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/leg_front.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Front leg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/leg_back.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Back leg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/body.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Body&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/gorilla/blade.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Disc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/gorilla</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/gorilla</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Grandy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Grandy removes the pain from the freelancing process for both designers and clients with a marketplace for $1k projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For freelancers, Grandy makes it easy to consistently keep clients in the funnel and reduce effort on negotiations so they can spend more time actually focused on doing what they do well: designing. For clients, Grandy helps find top quality designers without the fear of shoddy work, poor communication, or out-of-control budgets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/mockup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mockup&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Grandy logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-browse.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-freelancers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-project-messages.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-project-overview.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-project-inspiration.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-signup.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grandy/grandy-signup-complete.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/grandy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/grandy</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Startup Shell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Content. Someday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/startupshell</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/startupshell</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Amation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Amation combines the extensive capabilities of SVG with the power of media tools and animation. Users animate vectors in a timeline-based editor suite (like After Effects) and can distribute them as native SVGs, in all their scalable glory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amation is for the design community. UI design workflows include prototyping interactions to communicate with developers. With Amation, designers can maintain a full vector workflow, ultimately saving time, easing distribution, and improving performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scalable Vector Graphic, or SVG, is an extremely powerful file format. SVG is often used for individual assets, but has media opportunities in motion graphics, animation, and video. While raster media (like GIFs and MP4s) are based on grids of pixels that lose quality when resized, SVGs are infinitely scalable and lite. Since they’re XML-based, Amation uses JavaScript to manipulate the code and create packaged, native SVG media files that animate in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-web-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amation interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding new files by dragging on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-web-1-dragdrop.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amation drag-n-drop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dialog box with delete confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-web-1-dialog.png&quot; alt=&quot;Amation dialog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a quick demo of the product in use after about 24 hours of building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/pmm7UmDyQyE?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- And finally, here is a sample interaction created with Amation.

![Amation sample](/assets/amation/amation-sample.svg)
 --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recorded my screen while designing this project. This video will show my workflow and the many iterations that went into creating Amation. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/f_LtU9XXL8o?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We won the IBM Design prize at PennApps Fall 2014 for Amation. They generously flew us out to Austin, TX to visit the IBM Design team and talk more about Amation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-brainstorming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Brainstorming&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-david.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;David&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-dan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dan&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/amation/amation-ibmteam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Team at IBM Design&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/amation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/amation</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dot is a side-project I worked on with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/2neeraj&quot;&gt;Neeraj Baid&lt;/a&gt; while interning at Venmo. The goal was to create a one-gesture payments app powered by the Venmo API that promoted ephemeral transactions with photos. The app sought to test out some ideas floating around the Venmo team while providing an additional creative outlet for Neeraj and I to explore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot2-dr.png&quot; alt=&quot;Mockup&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-login.png&quot; alt=&quot;Login&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-people.png&quot; alt=&quot;People&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-gutter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Slide&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-pay.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pay&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-story.png&quot; alt=&quot;Story&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-walkthrough1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walkthrough 1&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-walkthrough2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walkthrough 2&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-walkthrough3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walkthrough 3&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-app-ios-walkthrough4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Walkthrough 4&quot; class=&quot;shadow center&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dot/dot-web-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Splash page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/dot</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/dot</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ADICU</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;ADI (Application Developer Institute) at Columbia University is an organization that teaches students how to code through various community events. I roomed with &lt;a href=&quot;http://danrs.ch&quot;&gt;Dan Schlosser&lt;/a&gt;, one of the ADI leaders, for my 2014 summer in New York, where we both worked at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jhil.co/venmo&quot;&gt;worked at Venmo&lt;/a&gt;. Together, we built the &lt;a href=&quot;http://adicu.com&quot;&gt;adicu.com&lt;/a&gt; website over the course of a couple weeks. I led design, while Dan led the front-end development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The guidelines for this design were maintaining a friendly and charming tone while inspiring a drive for technology education. In the spec that we prepared, Dan wrote that “ADI brings together Computer Science students.” This was the core principle behind the organization, and I wanted the design to reflect that, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of that, the site was complex in terms of the types of content it had to serve. There are events, blog posts, subscription fields, general informative content, resources and projects, learning guides, and so on. The site is powered by &lt;a href=&quot;http://danrs.ch/blog/post-2014-09-26#read&quot;&gt;Eventum&lt;/a&gt;, a fantastic publishing platform created from scratch by Dan. My design had to surface all this content to the front-page while placing emphasis on events (which is ADI’s main hook for new members). At the same time, each module of the site must be robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few iterations, we settled on this design. It was inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativemornings.com/talks&quot;&gt;Creative Mornings&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly&quot;&gt;General Assembly&lt;/a&gt; among other sites which shared similar values with ADI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/adicu/adi-web.png&quot; alt=&quot;ADI website&quot; class=&quot;shadow&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a mockup for the home page, which establishes the design language and major modules. Then Dan and I paired to code a few of the other pages based on these template elements. I left Dan and his team with this new ADI design language to continue building out future pages. The visual style can also be used in non-web ADI assets, such as posters or apparel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also worked on a few logo concepts, which ended up going unused by the organization. The goal here was to clearly show a technology association while still emitting welcoming vibes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/adicu/adi-logo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;ADI logo concept&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other logo ideas included using a &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt;_&lt;/code&gt; motif with the typography, but visually, it wasn’t appealing. I still love how this concept turned out and might use that typography style in a future project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/adicu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/adicu</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Venmo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Content. Someday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/venmo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/venmo</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bitcamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Content. Someday.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/bitcamp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/bitcamp</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Splitsies</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;current-situation&quot;&gt;Current Situation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splitting bills ain’t fun. It’s slow and awkward to figure out who owes whom how much… and when and in what denomination… and so on. The end of a dinner should be for socializing on a full stomach and appreciating the wonderful last hour spent with friends or family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All too often this time is committed to breaking out the calculators to work out the line-item expenditures, leaving all parties in a state of perpetual confusion and favor asking. Most of the time, despite all efforts, a group will beg a waiter to prepare separate checks or someone ends up throwing in and extra $20 “just to be done with it.”
Several bill splitting tools exist, but none attack this core problem of slow transactions. Most apps seem to focus on accuracy not speed, with half-baked receipt scanning features and gimmicky UIs. See for yourself: https://play.google.com/store/search?q=bill%20splitter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;solution&quot;&gt;Solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splitsies is a no-frills approach to splitting bill that is designed for speed. One designated payee covers the table’s bill, divides the total up on the app, and collects payment from others in the group. The central interaction is in a graph of each person’s portion of the total bill, represented by adjustable bars.
For example, if four people go out for milkshakes, and only Beth gets a pricier “Deluxe Megashake,” McKinley can just input the total bill and then pull up Beth’s bar accordingly.
By connecting with Facebook, users can easily charge directly to Venmo, or alternatively, an amount can be paid out in cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audience--behaviors&quot;&gt;Audience &amp;amp; Behaviors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app is aimed at users who go out with a group of friends on a regular basis. Each transaction will not exactly match the correct line item amount per person, but over time these numbers will average out amongst friends. Plus, when you’re already a few drinks in, it’s hard to care about an extra buck here and there. The Splitsies method is not for everyone, but is a quick, easy, and fun tool for those willing to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scene&quot;&gt;Scene&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Splitsies was inspired by apps like Level and Robinhood. These are financial tools that simplify daunting tasks that have previously required more infrastructure. While this minimalist approach limits functionality, it consolidates the user experience to be useful and focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;screens&quot;&gt;Screens&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-pt1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-pt2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-7-new_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-8-review_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-5-friends_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-12-menu_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-13-archive_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-14-archive-single_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-3-connect-pop_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-15-sms_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-16-web-pending_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/splitsies/app-v-11-success_framed.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;process&quot;&gt;Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the breakdown of project time over the course of two days. Research and brainstorming, 2 hours; observation, 1 hour; wireframing, 30 minutes; design and mockups, 6 hours; animation, 8 hours; presentation and final touches, 1 hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Observation” involved me going to Maryland’s Cornerstone Grill with three friends to experience a bill splitting situation while consciously paying attention to the interactions. Here, I saw the lack of care paid to the different items on the receipts, and overall cumbersomeness as my friends fumbled for their wallets. It was interesting to see my friends ask how much others were putting in and how that influenced their payments. This inspired the group-focused, ratio-based approach to bill splitting as seen in Splitsies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://jhil.co/splitsies</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jhil.co/splitsies</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
